{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following is a drug that interferes with the process of DNA production in the virus that causes genital herpes?", "opta": "Erythromycin", "optb": "Vancomycin", "optc": "Amantadine", "optd": "Acyclovir", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the antibiotic is not used as a food preservative ?", "opta": "Pimaricin", "optb": "Nisin", "optc": "Tylosin", "optd": "\u03b2-lactam antibiotic", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most selective antibiotics are those that interfere with the synthesis of", "opta": "bacterial DNA", "optb": "bacterial RNA", "optc": "bacterial cell walls", "optd": "bacterial plasma membrane", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cycloserine inhibits", "opta": "alanine racemase", "optb": "D-alanyl - D-alanine synthetase", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "amidase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which antibiotic has a beta-lactam ring?", "opta": "Cephalosporin", "optb": "Penicillin", "optc": "Tetracycline", "optd": "Streptomycin", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chemotherapeutic agents must", "opta": "prevent/destroy the activity of a parasite", "optb": "leave unaltered the host's natural defense mechanisms", "optc": "be able to come in contact with the parasite by penetrating the cells", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Novobiocin can be used against", "opta": "gram +ve Staphylococci", "optb": "gram -ve Meningococci & Gonococci", "optc": "Haemophilus", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Interference mechanism of ciprofloxacin and norfloxacin is due to their action on", "opta": "cell wall synthesis", "optb": "cell membrane function", "optc": "DNA function", "optd": "protein synthesis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "By which of the following means antifungal chemotherapeutic agents may affect fungi?", "opta": "Interfere with nuclear division by preventing the aggregation of microtubules needed for mitosis", "optb": "Interfere with normal nucleic acid synthesis", "optc": "Interfere with ergosterol biosynthesis and thus alter the structure of the cytoplasmic membrane as well as the function of several membrane-bound enzymes like those involved in nutrient transport and chitin synthesis", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following methods would be most appropriate for sterilizing an antibiotic solution?", "opta": "Dry heat sterilization", "optb": "Microfiltration", "optc": "Autoclaving", "optd": "Desiccation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following drugs involves modification of the drug by enzymatic modification or degradation of its active element to alter its/their resistance?", "opta": "Pencillins", "optb": "Choloramphenicol", "optc": "Aminoglyosides", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Who developed the concept of specific toxicity?", "opta": "Pasteur", "optb": "Fleming", "optc": "Watson", "optd": "Ehrlich", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When using alcohol as an antiseptic, which concentration is considered most effective?", "opta": "95%", "optb": "50%", "optc": "70%", "optd": "25%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fluoroquinolones are antibiotics which inhibit", "opta": "DNA polymerase", "optb": "RNA polymerase", "optc": "DNA gyrase", "optd": "Cross-linking of peptidoglycan", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is used only in life-threatening situations when no other drug is adequate?", "opta": "Penicillin", "optb": "Tetracycline", "optc": "Chloramphenicol", "optd": "Streptomycin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The susceptibility of a microorganism to antibiotics and other chemotherapeutic agents can be determined by using", "opta": "tube dilution technique", "optb": "paper disk plate", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most antibiotics are isolated from", "opta": "viruses", "optb": "aquatic microorganisms", "optc": "soil microorganisms", "optd": "plants", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following group is not the carbohydrate containing antibiotic?", "opta": "Streptomycin & Streptothricin", "optb": "Vancomycin & Moenomycin", "optc": "Everninomycin & Nogirimycin", "optd": "Erythromycin & candicidin", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The penicillin stable in gastric acid and suitable for oral administration is", "opta": "methicillin", "optb": "carbenicillin", "optc": "closacillin", "optd": "pencillin-G", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an example of potent antitumer agents?", "opta": "Anthramycin", "optb": "Sibromycin", "optc": "Neothramycin", "optd": "Erythromycin", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "More promising chemotherapeutic agents for treating viral diseases is", "opta": "leukocytic interferon", "optb": "fibroblast interferon", "optc": "interferon", "optd": "nystatin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A parenteral route of drug administration refers to", "opta": "oral", "optb": "nonoral", "optc": "intravenously", "optd": "intramuscularly", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following antibiotics can't be used for treatment of infections with \u03b2-lactamase-producing Staphylococcus aureus?", "opta": "Vancomycin", "optb": "Ampicillin/sulbactam", "optc": "Cephalothin", "optd": "Piperacillin", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an aminoglycoside antibiotic?", "opta": "Streptomycin", "optb": "Neomycin", "optc": "Kanamycin", "optd": "Cephalosporin", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nitrofurans differ from the antibiotics in that they", "opta": "do not occur naturally", "optb": "occur naturally", "optc": "are antimicrobial drugs", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Quinolones are", "opta": "antimetabolites", "optb": "penicillin derivatives", "optc": "bacteriostatic", "optd": "broad-spectrum", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a semi synthetic chemotherapeutic agent?", "opta": "Ampicillin", "optb": "Carbenicillin", "optc": "Penicillin", "optd": "Sulfonamide", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following tests is used to determine the minimal lethal concentration?", "opta": "Broth dilution test", "optb": "Agar dilution test", "optc": "Dilution susceptibility tests", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mode of action of polymyxin is to", "opta": "inhibit protein synthesis", "optb": "inhibit DNA synthesis", "optc": "injury to the plasma membrane", "optd": "inhibit folic acid synthesis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Polyene antibiotics are", "opta": "large ring structures", "optb": "\u03b2-lactam - thiazolidine ring", "optc": "small ring structures", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following may cause resistance to penicillin?", "opta": "Impermeability of cell envelope", "optb": "Production of \u03b2-lactamases by bacteria", "optc": "Alteration or lack of penicillin-binding proteins", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The third generation cephalosporin agents is", "opta": "cefotaxime", "optb": "cefoxitin", "optc": "cephalothin", "optd": "cephalexin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The penicillin resistant to \u03b2-lactamases is", "opta": "carbenicillin", "optb": "closacillin", "optc": "penicillin-G", "optd": "ampicillin", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The antibiotics not clinically useful for Pseudomonas aeruginosa infection is", "opta": "aminoglycosides", "optb": "ceftazidime", "optc": "piperacillin", "optd": "trimethoprim-sulphamethoxazole", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following drugs may show plasmid-mediated resistance?", "opta": "Nalidixic acid", "optb": "Ampicillin", "optc": "Rifampicin", "optd": "Methicillin", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The scientist who first discovered the substance penicillin was", "opta": "Joseph Lister", "optb": "Alexander Fleming", "optc": "Paul Ehrlich", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The larger the __________ , the better the chemotherapeutic agent.", "opta": "therapeutic index", "optb": "therapeutic dose", "optc": "selective toxicity", "optd": "spectrum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chelate forming peptide antibiotic are/is", "opta": "bleomycins", "optb": "sideromycins", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "vancomycin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With which of the following aminoglycosides interfere?", "opta": "Protein synthesis", "optb": "DNA function", "optc": "Cell wall synthesis", "optd": "Cell membrane function", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following protein synthesis mechanisms may be affected by particular drugs?", "opta": "Peptide bond formation", "optb": "mRNA translocation", "optc": "Aminoacyl-tRNA binding", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The antibiotics not having good activity against Enterobacteriaceae is", "opta": "clindamycin", "optb": "cefoxitin", "optc": "trimethoprim-sulphamethoxazole", "optd": "ciprofloxacin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Quinones and related antibiotics are", "opta": "tetracyclines", "optb": "actinorhodin", "optc": "mitomycin", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Both penicillin and fluoroquinolones", "opta": "bind to and inactivate a bacterial protein", "optb": "inhibit the cross-linking of peptidoglycan", "optc": "are inactivated by \u03b2-lactamase", "optd": "must be transported into the cytoplasm in order to act", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A broad-spectrum antibiotic such as chloramphenicol is one that", "opta": "kills both Gram positive and Gram negative bacteria", "optb": "kills all bacteria", "optc": "kills numerous types of microbes", "optd": "kills all microorganisms", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vancomycin inhibits peptidoglycan synthesis by binding", "opta": "D-alanyl - D-alanine", "optb": "alanine racemase", "optc": "D-alanyl - D-alanine synthetase", "optd": "amidase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nystatin is a drug used for treatment of diseases caused by", "opta": "gram negative bacterium", "optb": "gram positive bacterium", "optc": "yeast", "optd": "protozoan", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an amino acid and peptide antibiotic?", "opta": "Penicillin", "optb": "Actinomycin", "optc": "Bacitracin", "optd": "Tetranactin", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cephalosporins and Penicillins interfere with which of the following?", "opta": "Protein synthesis", "optb": "DNA function", "optc": "Cell membrane function", "optd": "Cell wall synthesis", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacterial cells susceptible to penicillium can be protected from destruction if the medium in which they are exposed is of", "opta": "high osmotic pressure", "optb": "low osmotic pressure", "optc": "moderate osmotic pressure", "optd": "high surface tension", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The compound(s) which act(s) as metabolic antagonist is/are", "opta": "trimethoprim", "optb": "sulphonamides", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Amphotericin B and polymyxin interfere with", "opta": "cell wall synthesis", "optb": "protein synthesis", "optc": "cell membrane function", "optd": "DNA function", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not \u03b2-lactamase-resistant penicillin?", "opta": "Oxacillin", "optb": "Nafcillin", "optc": "Carbenicillin", "optd": "Methicillin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The antibiotics which affords a broad spectrum of antimicrobial coverage against aerobic and anaerobic bacteria, rickettsiae, chlamydiae, and mycoplasmas is", "opta": "gentamicin", "optb": "tetracycline", "optc": "metronidazole", "optd": "vancomycin", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}